<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Craig's Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Craig Palermo's personal blog]]></description><link>https://craigpalermo.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:02:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Building This Site with GitHub Actions]]></title><description><![CDATA[Yesterday, I was making some updates to this site and noticed that the process to publish updates was somewhat tedious.
In order to publish…]]></description><link>https://craigpalermo.com/building-this-site-with-github-actions/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://craigpalermo.com/building-this-site-with-github-actions/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I was making some updates to this site and noticed that the process to publish updates was somewhat tedious.
In order to publish a change, I would need to manually run &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;npm run build&lt;/code&gt;, commit and push the changes, then
return the the GitHub repo’s settings to change the custom domain for GitHub pages back to &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;craigpalermo.com&lt;/code&gt;. For
some reason, this kept resetting each time I pushed changes to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/code&gt; folder. I figured it had something to do
with the fact that I was serving the site from a custom directory, but I wasn’t sure exactly why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I had the inclination to try replicating this process with GitGub Actions. I hadn’t used Actions before, so I
thought this would be a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I modified the default Node.js action to create &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/craigpalermo/craigpalermo.com/blob/master/.github/workflows/main.yml&quot;&gt;this simple workflow&lt;/a&gt;.
It performs the following steps whenever &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Checks out the repo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installs NPM dependencies and Gatsby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Builds Gatsby static site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commits changes (thanks to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/marketplace/actions/add-commit&quot;&gt;marketplace action&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gitname/react-gh-pages/issues/19#issuecomment-436148409&quot;&gt;This answer&lt;/a&gt; also explained why my
custom domain kept resetting and provided a simple fix that I could add to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;npm build&lt;/code&gt; script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I’ve only just started with GitHub Actions, I’m pleasantly surprised at how easy it makes setting up
a simple cloud CI environment with almost no configuration. Its email notifications sent to your GitHub
account email are also a nice way to receive updates about your build status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I’ll never have to worry about where this site is hosted or how it’s deployed; all I have to do is push
changes to the Markdown or React content and GitHub takes care of the rest, for free!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Now's More Than Ever]]></title><description><![CDATA[If you’ve ever worked in an organization divided into multiple teams,
segmented by product, let’s say, then you may have heard of an…]]></description><link>https://craigpalermo.com/nows-more-than-ever/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://craigpalermo.com/nows-more-than-ever/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever worked in an organization divided into multiple teams,
segmented by product, let’s say, then you may have heard of an interesting
idea from another team that you’ve wanted to implement for your own.
You feel that their workflow, library, or the like could similarly
benefit your team. However, you haven’t the time allocated to put it
into practice. You’d need to justify to your higher-ups that it would
be worth the investment, and your audience’s technical experience
can make this any level of difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my experience, making the investment in the ways and means to improve
a team’s quality of life, developer experience, and ostensibly the
quality of the product early on can pay dividends later. The product
and team culture will benefit from avoiding taking on new technical
debt and producing more stable solutions from the start, as well as at
each step of iteration, in addition to the perpetual excitement of
staying ahead of the curve. Would you rather you and your team suffer through
months of uncomfortable and frustrating steps in your daily workflow,
or can you avoid it all by acting today? In the long run, now’s worth a lot
more than ever. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Importance of Casual Cross-Team Collaboration]]></title><description><![CDATA[After a year and a half at my current job, I’ve started to do something
different over the past couple months. Whenever I get the chance, I…]]></description><link>https://craigpalermo.com/cross-team-collaboration/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://craigpalermo.com/cross-team-collaboration/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;After a year and a half at my current job, I’ve started to do something
different over the past couple months. Whenever I get the chance, I try
to chat with engineers from other teams. It may seem obvious, but in the
course of these casual conversations, I’ve learned a lot about how other
teams work within the organization and have even shared solutions
between our teams to the benefit of the entire organization. Had we not
taken the opportunity to familiarize ourselves with our
counterparts from other product teams, we would have missed out on
these shared wins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save for organized company meetings, developers (and really employees in any role)
at companies of all sizes and layouts may not have the opportunity to organically
share their ideas and work product with members of other teams. This
includes anything from common components usable by many applications
to best practices that could benefit multiple teams. While Slack channels
and quarterly all-hands meetings help to share big-picture successes, nothing
beats talk over coffee when you want to get informal exposure for your
pet project before it’s ready for prime time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, teams might be divided by office, geolocation, and timezone,
making it even harder to get to know your neighbor. Plenty of resources
can help teams better manage the challenges of remote work, but the idea
remains the same. This effort can pay off greatly by allowing teams
to share their best ideas, even when they’re not scheduled into anyone’s
quarterly goals.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Effect of Background JS Processes on UX Performance with React]]></title><description><![CDATA[My team recently encountered a problem with a React slider component.
We spent a while investigating the root cause, but couldn’t identify
a…]]></description><link>https://craigpalermo.com/slider-perf-demo/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://craigpalermo.com/slider-perf-demo/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 18:00:23 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;My team recently encountered a problem with a React slider component.
We spent a while investigating the root cause, but couldn’t identify
a single source of the problem. However, I noticed that enabling an
ad blocker to prevent 3rd party scripts from loading seemed to help.
These scripts (everything from ads to tracking to fraud prevention)
added numerous event listeners that would invoke functions on the same
interactions that our component in question, in this case a range
slider, needed to function. This caused the slider to become
monetarily unresponsive and drastically decreased frame rates. This
prevented React from making the necessary DOM updates to reflect user
interactions, making it ultimately unusable from a UX
perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To see if I could recreate this effect, I wrote a simple application to
simulate blocking work on the main thread that would delay React’s
rendering, causing a framerate drop and the UI to become unresponsive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://craigpalermo.github.io/slider-perf-demo&quot;&gt;live demo&lt;/a&gt;
and try adjusting the parameters. The effects are especially noticeable
on mobile devices, which we cannot forget to account for in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reading List 2019]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’ve always had trouble finishing books once I’ve started them. New titles make their way
onto the list, and inevitably pull me away from…]]></description><link>https://craigpalermo.com/2019-reading-list/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://craigpalermo.com/2019-reading-list/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’ve always had trouble finishing books once I’ve started them. New titles make their way
onto the list, and inevitably pull me away from those in progress before I’ve
finished. This year, I’m trying to break this habit by maintaining a reading list, which
I hope will keep my choices more focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Books I’ve finished in 2019:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Make-Your-Bed-Little-Things/dp/1455570249/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1JB12WJ3B2X0J&amp;#x26;keywords=make+your+bed&amp;#x26;qid=1550084523&amp;#x26;s=gateway&amp;#x26;sprefix=make+your%2Caps%2C137&amp;#x26;sr=8-1&quot;&gt;Make Your Bed: Little Things That Can Change Your Life…And Maybe the World&lt;/a&gt; by William H. McRaven&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Unfu-Yourself-Your-Head-into/dp/0062803832/ref=sr_1_1?crid=3JRLRUPS9M6MH&amp;#x26;keywords=unfuk+yourself&amp;#x26;qid=1550084578&amp;#x26;s=gateway&amp;#x26;sprefix=unf%2Caps%2C126&amp;#x26;sr=8-1&quot;&gt;Unfu*k Yourself&lt;/a&gt; by Gary John Bishop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Fifth-Risk-Michael-Lewis/dp/1324002646&quot;&gt;The Fifth Risk&lt;/a&gt; Michael Lewis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Threat-Protects-America-Terror-Trump/dp/1250207576&quot;&gt;The Threat: How the FBI Protects America in the Age of Terror and Trump&lt;/a&gt; Andrew G. McCabe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title><description><![CDATA[Welcome to my new home page! I haven’t taken the time lately to write,
so I figured the first step would be to get a new notebook. This will…]]></description><link>https://craigpalermo.com/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://craigpalermo.com/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 17:41:23 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my new home page!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t taken the time lately to write,
so I figured the first step would be to get a new notebook. This will serve as a medium
for me to document recent work, random thoughts, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>